<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.arthurnjh.me</id>
    <title>ArthurGuinness&apos; blog</title>
    <updated>2019-05-29T14:32:41.230Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.arthurnjh.me"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://www.arthurnjh.me/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to my space&lt;h2&gt;</subtitle>
    <logo>https://www.arthurnjh.me/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://www.arthurnjh.me/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2019, ArthurGuinness&apos; blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[近思]]></title>
        <id>https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/近思</id>
        <link href="https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/近思">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-05-29T12:57:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>许久，感到孤独。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>许久，感到孤独。</p>
<!--more-->
<p>时而在暗夜，时而在阴雨，也时而在晴空下。</p>
<p>可能是因为性格使然。时常想法颇多，却陷于不会表达，不愿表达。因此错过了许多缘分，包括友情，包括爱情。
现在依然如此，像是害怕与人交往太深，也像是懒得交往太深。似乎打小就有一种想法刻在心里，所谓朋友，心意大抵相通，不拘小节，不藏心机，但各自坚守底线。在现实中我与人也即是按这个标准来做的。似乎来者不拒，有人接近就试着当成朋友相处，可过了一段时间就会发现，好像不适合相处太深，如果没有什么必要的相处机会就会渐渐淡了。</p>
<p>也谈过几次恋爱，可惜没有一段是真正走心的，似乎大家只是想找个人陪着，等到不需要或者腻了就立马分开。所以至今还没有人真正了解我，也许包括我自己。</p>
<p>其实这种突然而来的孤独感好像是每个人都有的。我把它理解成<code>身体对自己一段时间强压力下生活的一种强制放松。</code></p>
<p>因为这种感觉总是在我经历一段<a href="%E8%BF%99%E9%87%8C%E7%9A%84%E5%85%85%E5%AE%9E%E5%8F%AF%E4%BB%A5%E7%90%86%E8%A7%A3%E4%B8%BA%E7%94%A8%E5%90%84%E7%A7%8D%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E5%A1%AB%E5%85%85%E8%87%AA%E5%B7%B1%E7%9A%84%E7%94%9F%E6%B4%BB%EF%BC%8C%E5%8C%85%E6%8B%AC%E5%83%8F%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F%EF%BC%8C%E8%BF%BD%E5%89%A7%E7%AD%89%E5%A8%B1%E4%B9%90%E3%80%82">“充实”</a>生活之后才出现的，像是在连续几场考试之后，一次长时间的时间较紧的活动之后甚至期间。</p>
<p>因为出现的时间不定，所以不会有预防措施，只有尽量去缓解，或者等待它自己消失，然后继续充实的生活。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Python初试]]></title>
        <id>https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/python初试</id>
        <link href="https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/python初试">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-05-28T13:20:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>最近在做一个关于机器人的项目，需要接收和分析卫星定位数据，并把位置显示到地图上。初次尝试，只用python写了一个简单的读取脚本，记录一下注意事项。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>最近在做一个关于机器人的项目，需要接收和分析卫星定位数据，并把位置显示到地图上。初次尝试，只用python写了一个简单的读取脚本，记录一下注意事项。</p>
<!--more-->
<p>前期学了几天python，也简单了解了NEMA 0183协议和GNSS接收机的命令和数据收取。
经过在网上学习了很多别人的代码后，我完成了以下脚本：</p>
<pre><code class="language-Python">#设置脚本编码
#coding=utf-8

#导入必要的模块，这里的pynmea2暂时没有用到，下面解释它的用处
import serial
import pynmea2
import time

#配置并打开串口，这里是在Windows下的串口
ser = serial.Serial(&quot;COM4&quot;,115200)
ser.timeout = 2 #设置超时时间为两秒
ser.parity = &quot;N&quot; #设置校验码为无

#检测串口是否打开
def Open():
    if ser.isOpen():
        print(&quot;serial is opened.&quot;)
    else:
        ser.open()
        print('serial is restarted.')

				#发送命令
def SendDate(i_msg):
    i_msg = i_msg + &quot;\r\n&quot; #要加上换行回车符表示命令传输完成
    try:
        i_msg = i_msg.encode('ascii') #将string字符串转换为byte字节
        ser.write(i_msg) #发送命令
    except Exception as ex:
        print(ex)

#开始执行
if __name__ == &quot;__main__&quot;:
    Open()
    SendDate(&quot;KSXT 1&quot;)
    while 1:
        line = ser.readline() #读取数据，这里是按行读取，遇到&quot;\n&quot;结束
        line = line.decode('ascii') #将读取出来的byte型转为string型
        print(line)
</code></pre>
<p>注意事项：</p>
<ol>
<li>如果用的readline读取一定要设置timeout，否则可能造成阻塞</li>
<li>注意发送数据一定要转换成字符型，否则会直接报错</li>
<li>命令要加上&quot;\r\n&quot;作为结束标志</li>
<li>serial读出来的数据为byte型，要通过decode方法解码成string型，编码按接收的数据来设置</li>
</ol>
<p>下一步的工作：</p>
<ol>
<li>利用<a href="http://www.gnss.help/2018/03/01/pynmea2-readme/">pynmea2</a>解析数据，取出经纬度，海拔和航向等数据。</li>
<li>利用ROS在Ubuntu上读取数据，实现以上筛选。</li>
<li>将读取的位置信息显示在地图上（可以利用各大地图的API实现）。</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fight For Liberty]]></title>
        <id>https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/fight-for-liberty</id>
        <link href="https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/fight-for-liberty">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-05-26T10:50:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-final-speech-of-the-great-dictator">The Final Speech of &quot;the Great Dictator&quot;</h3>
<p>这篇文章选自卓别林的经典电影《大独裁者》最后的演讲部分，第一次看到感触很深，收藏下来，共勉。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-final-speech-of-the-great-dictator">The Final Speech of &quot;the Great Dictator&quot;</h3>
<p>这篇文章选自卓别林的经典电影《大独裁者》最后的演讲部分，第一次看到感触很深，收藏下来，共勉。</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I'm sorry, but I don't want to be an emperor. That's not my business. I don't want to rule or conquer anyone. I should like to help everyone if possible - Jew, Gentile - black man - white.</p>
<p>We all want to help one another. Human beings are like that. We want to live by each other's happiness - not by each other's misery. We don't want to hate an despise one another. In this world there's room for everyone and the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone.</p>
<p>The way of life can be free and beautiful, but we have lost the way. Greed has poisoned men's souls - has barricaded the world with hate - has goose-stepped us into misery and bloodshed. We have developed speed, but we have shut ourselves in. Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want. Our knowledge has made us cynical; our cleverness, hard and unkind. We think too much and feel too little. More than machinery we need humanity. More than cleverness, we need kindness and gentleness. Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost. The aeroplane and the radio have brought us closer together. The very nature of these inventions cries out for the goodness in man - cries for universal brotherhood - for the unity of us all. Even now my voice is reaching millions throughout the world - millions of despairing men, women, and little children - victims of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people. To those who can hear me, I say: 'Do not despair.' The misery that is now upon us is but the passing of greed - the bitterness of men who fear the way of human progress. The hate of men will pass, and dictators die, and the power they took from the people will return to the people. And so long as men die, liberty will never perish.</p>
<p>Soldiers! Don't give yourselves to brutes - men who despise you and enslave you - who regiment your lives - tell you what to do - what to think and what to feel! Who drill you - diet you - treat you like cattle, use you as cannon fodder. Don't give yourselves to these unnatural men - machine men with machine minds and machine hearts! You are not machines! You are not cattle! You are men! You have the love of humanity in your hearts. You don't hate, only the unloved hate - the unloved and the unnatural!</p>
<p>Soldiers! Don't fight for slavery! Fight for liberty! In the seventeenth chapter of St Luke, it is written the kingdom of God is within man not one man nor a group of men, but in all men! In you! You, the people, have the power - the power to create machines. The power to create happiness! You, the people, have the power to make this life free and beautiful - to make this life a wonderful adventure. Then in the name of democracy - let us use that power - let us all unite. Let us fight for a new world - a decent world that will give men a chance to work - that will give youth a future and old age a security.</p>
<p>By the promise of these things, brutes have risen to power. But they lie! They do not fulfil that promise. They never will! Dictators free themselves but they enslave the people. Now let us fight to fulfil that promise! Let us fight to free the world - to do away with national barriers - to do away with greed, with hate and intolerance. Let us fight for a world f reason - a world where science and progress will lead to all men's happiness. Soldiers, in the name of democracy let us unite!</p>
<p>Hannah, can you hear me? Wherever you are, look up Hannah. The clouds are lifting! The sun is breaking through! We are coming out of the darkness into the light. We are coming into a new world - a kindlier world, where men will rise above their hate, their greed and their brutality. Look up, Hannah! The soul of man has been given wings and at last he is beginning to fly. He is flying into the rainbow - into the light of hope, into the future, the glorious future that belongs to you, to me, and to all of us. Look up, Hannah... look up!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[关于五四运动的一些想法]]></title>
        <id>https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/关于五四运动的一些想法</id>
        <link href="https://www.arthurnjh.me/post/关于五四运动的一些想法">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-05-26T09:23:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>距离五四运动一百周年纪念已经过去很多天了，我也一直在看好奇心日报当天发出的文章，事务繁多，拖到现在才看的差不多，谈一谈自己的一些想法，不太成熟，引用了别人的文章表述的清楚一点。</p>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>距离五四运动一百周年纪念已经过去很多天了，我也一直在看好奇心日报当天发出的文章，事务繁多，拖到现在才看的差不多，谈一谈自己的一些想法，不太成熟，引用了别人的文章表述的清楚一点。</p>
<!--more-->
<p>五四运动作为一场中国人的文化启蒙运动已经过去整整一百年了，而五四带来影响却延续至今，可见其历史地位至关重要。
毫无疑问，五四在当时的意义是带回西方民主思想的留学生希冀通过呼唤解放与自由来唤醒中国人的思想，进而拯救岌岌可危的中国。可见，五四运动的深层动力是“救亡”，带有深层次的民族主义，这也是它异于西方启蒙运动之处和被定性为爱国主义运动或民族主义运动的原因，以下引述高克力在《五四的思想世界》中的一段话：</p>
<blockquote>
<p>中国的启蒙运动源于寻求国家富强的民族主义目标，因而启蒙始终与民族主义结伴而行。这也是中国启蒙异于欧洲启蒙之处，欧洲启蒙时代的个人主义精神毋宁是世界主义的。所谓‘救亡压倒启蒙’之说，显然忽略了中西启蒙的历史差异以及中国启蒙的民族主义关怀。实际上，中国启蒙的深层动力正是‘救亡’，与欧洲人文主义式启蒙相比，中国启蒙毋宁说是一种落后民族寻求富强之道的‘救亡型启蒙’。在中国现代化运动中，西方一直以强盗兼导师的矛盾形象而出现。它一方面代表了自由民主的现代文明，另一方面又是欺凌掠夺东方民族的帝国主义者。与西方文明的自由主义与帝国主义两面神相对应，中国现代化运动和启蒙思潮，亦有亲西方的自由主义与反西方的民族主义两种趋向。中国现代思想之‘反西方的西方化’和‘反现代的现代化’的矛盾取向，即源于此。因而，民族主义之于中国启蒙，始终是一把双刃剑，它既可成为驱策启蒙的精神动力，又可成为抗拒启蒙和现代性的保守因素。”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>无论如何评价，它在过去的一百年里给中国的文化和社会意识形态带来的影响是不可磨灭的。而五四运动之所以意义深远，在于我们仍然在不断地对它进行回溯和接续，阐释其的历史意义及使命，并从中探寻中国人的自由与民主之路。即使再过一百年，当我们谈到五四运动还是会肃然起敬，还是会有启发和感触。这场充满智慧与光明的运动就像是给青年人的激励和警醒，无论何时都会散发光芒。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>